Liguo Cheng

Manager, Clinical Programming at WuXi CDS

clg335@163.com

Summary

Experienced in project management, timeline/resource planning, especially in collaborating with CRO team; Excellent at SAS programming including base SAS, Graph, Macro, ect., have been the SAS certified advanced programmer for SAS9 since Dec 2009;

Experienced in the design of mock-up TLGs for statistical analysis;

Experienced in the CDISC standards, especially in SDTM and ADaM;

Familiar with the data and reporting requirements for CFDA, FDA, EMA, ect;

Personality: confident, proactive, team player.

Experience

Manager, Clinical Programming at WuXi Clinical Development Service

September 2014 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Team Management;

Resource Planning;

Senior Statistical Programmer Analyst at Roche

September 2010 - September 2014 (4 years 1 month)

Daily work: review eCRF, design mock-up of TLGs, generate TLGs for CSR submission, collaborate/manage CRO team members, ect.

Project:

I have been working on 5 studies from Ph I to III, mainly focusing on Oncology and other TA:

- 1. NSCLC: a phase III regional registry oncology study, which lasts almost 4 years, I worked as project lead and managed team members from local and global CRO to ensure successfully delivering safety (AE and demographic) and efficacy (PFS, BORR, OS) outputs with high quality within tight timeline. And I also worked with IDMC to ensure IDCC to deliver the outputs for the interim analysis. I also performed the biomarker analysis for this study.
- 2. NHL/CLL: a phase I oncology study, as a project lead, I managed local CRO team members to perform PK and safety analysis for CFDA submission.
- 3. Melanoma: a phase I&III oncology study, as a project lead, I managed local CRO team members to perform PK, safety and efficacy (PFS, BORR, OS) analysis for CFDA submission.

- 4. CNS: a phase I CNS study, as a project lead, I managed local CRO team members to perform PK and safety analysis for CFDA submission.
- 5. Chronic Renal Anemia: a pivot phase III study, as the study programmer, I was responsible for generating the TLGs with high quality for CSR within timeline.

Non-project:

- 1. As host of knowledge sharing forum to encourage the learning and sharing within team;
- 2. As PKS Superuser to collaborate with global team and as communication bridge between global and APAC;
- 3. As rep of APAC to attending the global DQSR workshop;
- 4. As APAC Biometrics Organizing Committee lead to plan and organize the department team building and all hands meeting activities;
- 5. As oral speaker to deliver a presentation about the Cox regression in PharmSUG China in 2013;
- 6. As poster presenter to attend the WUSS conference in Las Vegas in 2013.

Data analyst at PCCC(credit cards company)

June 2008 - August 2010 (2 years 3 months)

As data analyst, I was working on credit card data analysis including implementation CRM and Risk Management Plan by using SAS.

Languages

Chinese and English

Skills & Expertise

SAS

Statistical Programming

CDISC

Clinical Trials

Biostatistics

EDC

People Management

Clinical Research

GCP

Education

Nanjing Agricultural University

Master, Biostatistics, 2005 - 2008

Activities and Societies: Learned the basic knowledge of SAS programming, and practiced several kinds of statistical models (mixed linear model, regression, and logistic model) to analysis sample data.

Shanxi Agricultural University

Bachelor's degree, Biotechnology and Economics, 2001 - 2005 Activities and Societies: Got the basic knowledge about the Biotechnology and Economics.

Interests

Basketball

Liguo Cheng

Manager, Clinical Programming at WuXi CDS

clg335@163.com



Contact Liguo on LinkedIn